AVINASH "AVI" VALLABH, A+, N+

Huntington Beach, CA 92648 • (714) 425-2811 • avinash90@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/avallabh

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

A results-oriented professional with excellent qualifications on a **HELP DESK**, in **DESKTOP SUPPORT**, as an **IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST** and **IT CONSULTANT**. Command outstanding analytical and problem-solving skills. Interface effectively with all levels of clientele, vendors, staff, management and IT personnel. Successfully plan and coordinate all stages of complex projects. Dedicated to remaining continually current on new technologies.

Key Strengths Include:

- Installed hardware and systems, and maintained networks for multiple businesses and individuals.
- Communicate closely with clients to determine their precise requirements and ensure their complete satisfaction with finished work.
- Work well independently or as part of a collaborative team effort.
- Use strong troubleshooting talents to determine root causes of problems and implement optimal solutions.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

B.S. Degree / Business Administration / Accountancy ● California State University, Long Beach Worked as a Business Statistics Tutor

A.A. Degree • Orange Coast College - Costa Mesa, CA - VEX Robotics International Competitor - 2nd Place National Award

Certifications: CompTIA A+ CE • CompTIA Network+ CE • Certified Tax Preparer (Can Reinstate)

Computer Skills: Windows & Apple/Mac OS ● Linux Ubuntu ● MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Word)

Lightroom • Sophos • 1Password • Photoshop • Salesforce • FileZilla • Google Drive • Dropbox

Synology NAS • Hyper-V • Plex Media Server • Private Internet Access VPN • Oracle • Great Plains • Problem Solving Troubleshooting Hardware & Software for Small Businesses & Homes • Keyboarding to 60 wpm

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Consultant ● Self Employed

Provide a wide range of support to individuals and small businesses in Data Management, System Restoring & Backup, Network & System Administration, and Security. (2010 to Present)

- Managed data and workstations for a wedding photography service. Secured customer images and associated contracts. Also assisted in editing photos shot with the photographer at weddings with up to 1,000 guests.
- Maintained PC's and Macs for various clients. Recovered lost and failed hard drives. Conducted troubleshooting on uncommon software and hardware issues.
- Administered users and provided profile access and password recovery. Upgraded out failed and old PC components. Removed viruses and malware. Improved performance for aging and current PC's without hardware changes.

Accounting Specialist Temp • VACO - Irvine, CA

Completed an assignment for an e-commerce/retailer of handbags, tote bags and accessories. Analyzed costs of inventories and global supply chain. Processed invoice payments via full-cycle accounting procedures. Balanced accounts. *Created new processes that streamlined financial reporting, resulting in cost savings.* (2018)

Accounts Payable Temp • Robert Half - Irvine, CA

Served in the corporate offices of In-N-Out and Wynne Systems, a software engineering firm. Conducted a high volume of A/P reporting duties. Coordinated invoices for approval and distribution to appropriate departments and regions. *Used proprietary software within Oracle.* (2017 to 2018)

Accountant Temp • Artemis Search Partners - Irvine, CA

Worked as a Staff Accountant for Aspen Skilled Healthcare, a large health service provider. Prepared monthly G/L account entries. Reconciled 15 bank accounts against the G/L. Prepared financial statements. (2016)

Product Managing Intern / Wireless Consumer Products • D-Link Systems, Inc. - Fountain Valley, CA

Performed multiple functions for this manufacturer of network devices, such as routers and wireless adapters. Conducted software QA testing on various Windows systems. Also performed testing for a new antenna design product and online streaming service. Created and revised documentation. Assisted with marketing the company's product line to vendors at tradeshows. *Collaborated with R&D on various projects.* (2008 to 2010)

REFERENCES: Available upon Request COMPENSATION: Open to Negotiation